### DANIEL BOREN

2809 W William Cannon Dr #A203
Austin, TX, 78745
210-218-6248 (Cell phone)
danielboren@att.net | linkedin.com/in/daniel-boren-5b2b9864
dboren.github.io/db UpdatedPortfolio2/index.html | github.com/dboren

## **Summary**

Full stack web developer with a background in music and sound recording. Certified in full stack web development by the University of Texas of Austin Coding Boot Camp. Team player with keen attention to detail and a focus on delivering outstanding user experience.

## **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS, SQL

Applications: Github, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas, MySQL Workbench

Tools: Node, Express, Bootstrap, React, Mongoose, Bulma

# **Projects**

**Work From Home Relocator** | https://github.com/rachelamos/WFH-relocator | https://ancient-hollows-66162.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full stack React application allows users to search its database of cities in the United States to view information on their local broadband availability and cost-of-living index.
- Role: Programmer. Primarily developed the search function, researched broadband data, and set up Express routing. Assisted with debugging other aspects of code throughout development.
- Tools: React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Axios, ReCharts

Curatio | https://github.com/m-llo/Project-2-Team-6 | https://stormy-river-69253.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Full stack application which allows users to create curated playlists of YouTube videos relating to personal hobbies.
- Role: Programmer. Primarily worked on data model development, initial API route development, logout implementation, and dashboard page development. Assisted with debugging other aspects of code throughout development.
- Tools: Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, bcrypt, Nodemailer, YouTube API

**Nonprofit Locator** | https://github.com/riraq/Nonprofit\_Locator | https://riraq.github.io/Nonprofit\_Locator/

- Summary: Application allows user to search for animal and environment focused nonprofit organizations in the USA by city.
- Role: Programmer. Primarily added fetch functions utilizing the ProPublica Nonprofit Explorer API and added quick-search functionality. Assisted with debugging other aspects of code throughout development.
- Tools: ProPublica Nonprofit Explorer API, Bulma, Mapbox

# **Experience**

# Sound Designer at Mood Media August 2017 – September 2020

- Recorded, edited, and mixed promotional and informative audio messages for Mood clients.

## Tier 2 Customer Service Representative at Mood Media April 2017 – August 2017

 Provided technical support to Mood clients with a primary focus on digital signage platforms and their online control interfaces.

### Platinum Customer Service Representative at Mood Media October 2014 – April 2017

Provided white glove technical and general assistance to higher priority Mood clients, including
accommodating unique equipment setups and resolution processes tailored to specific clients'
needs, such as a specialized jukebox setup provided for Texas Roadhouse. Worked closely with
clients' respective Mood account managers to ensure timely and thorough resolution to clients'
requests.

## Customer Service Rep (Third Party Support) at Mood Media Aug 2014 – Oct 2014

 Provided customer service focused on Mood clients who use third party online service request systems, such as ServiceChannel.

#### Customer Service Representative at Mood Media June 2013 – August 2014

Provided technical and general assistance to Mood clients via both telephone and Mood's internal e-mail ticket queue. Mood Media is a company which provides branding solutions to clients in various forms, such as overhead and on-hold music and voice messaging, digital signage, and instore scents, with many services manageable by the user through online control websites.

## **Education**

### **UT Austin Coding Boot Camp**

Graduated with a certification in full stack web development in 2021

### Texas State University, San Marcos, TX

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with a Bachelor of Science in Sound Recording Technology and a minor in German in 2013 (GPA: 3.94)